<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>music on poolp.org</title><link>https://poolp.org/categories/music/</link><description>Recent content in music on poolp.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>poolp.org - All rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 12:31:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://poolp.org/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building my own guitar, part 3</title><link>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-07-04/building-my-own-guitar-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 12:31:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-07-04/building-my-own-guitar-part-3/</guid><description>TL;DR: Received the new neck and... it fits perfectly ! The neck UPS just delivered the new neck, which is a 24 frets PRS clone:
Not much to say about it, it is high quality Canadian Maple with Jatoba fretboard, feels nice, looks nice though it will not remain as is.
I did a fitting test and it fits perfectly:
The tools I have also received a set of tools for making small work on the body, like crafting contours:</description></item><item><title>Building my own guitar, part 2</title><link>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-06-29/building-my-own-guitar-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2023 13:22:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-06-29/building-my-own-guitar-part-2/</guid><description>TL;DR: Received the neck... too bad it's not exactly the one I ordered :-) The neck For the neck, I wanted a 24 frets neck and found one that I liked online.
Upon delivery today, I realized that they didn&amp;rsquo;t ship the correct one, but a 22 frets neck instead (see picture above). So while it still looks very nice, it&amp;rsquo;s not exacrly what I wanted, and it also doesn&amp;rsquo;t fit quite right in the body despite an announced compatible size: turns out that in guitar making, millimeters do matter.</description></item><item><title>Building my own guitar, part 1</title><link>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-06-28/building-my-own-guitar-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 13:42:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-06-28/building-my-own-guitar-part-1/</guid><description>TL;DR: I'm building a guitar from scratch, picking up every component but skipping the tricky cut and glue bits :-) About this project The primary goal of this project is to build a custom guitar, picking each and every component one by one, so that it&amp;rsquo;s 100% what I want it to be.
The second goal is to set myself a reasonnable objective, by not having to cut and glue wood myself, so that I can see if I like building guitars at all.</description></item><item><title>A new section appeared !</title><link>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-06-25/a-new-section-appeared/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2023 17:29:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://poolp.org/posts/2023-06-25/a-new-section-appeared/</guid><description>TL;DR: I will be discussing music on this blog from now on. This blog is a musical blog too As some of you know, I have a deep interest for music.
This blog section will focus on music-related topics, from a listener, amateur musician and/or producer point of view.
I will sometimes post links to music I want to share, either because I did it, or because I like it, but I will also write articles and share hardware and software reviews.</description></item></channel></rss>